Nagarjuna SK

Test Automation Lead Consultant

A Quality Engineering professional with 8 years of experience predominantly delivering Test Automation solutions relevant to Front-end and Back-end systems looking for an exciting assignment. Helping organizations to improve their applications quality, time to market, thereby enriching customer digital experience. Good exposure to Digital Transformation Projects & SaaS platforms.



- arjun.vceteee@gmail.com
- Chennai, India
- github.com/NagarjunaSK-Git

- +91-8883641747
- in linkedin.com/in/nagarjunask

WORK EXPERIENCE

Chapter Lead - Test EngineeringTata Consultancy Services

06/2021 - Present

Chennai

Roles & Achievements

- Drove the automation strategy across multiple teams, resulting in a significant increase in test automation adoption by incorporating trainings, proof of concept, test infrastructure and QA-Ops mindset which enhanced engineering culture.
- Handling a significant part to define the test automation objectives during the technical design, development, and maintenance to build an effective solution.
- Brought the culture of Continuous Testing in 3 sprints over the pipelines to reap the benefit of automation from the POC phase.
- Delivered a stable automation suite of 200+ scripts for the team from scratch by reducing 60% manual effort with significant test coverage.
- Delivered monthly releases across teams led to an increase in automation adoption from 20% to 60%, reducing testing efforts on API integration areas by 90%.
- Mentored a test team of 20 members having diverse cultures and enabled T shaping.

Automation - Consultant Capgemini

03/2020 - 06/2021

Chennai

Roles & Achievements

- Collaborate with Product Managers, Developers, and Stakeholders to understand requirements, and use cases to transform them into tests.
- Gain in-depth knowledge of the applications and actively identify areas of improvement for the framework stability and ease of maintenance.
- Created 500+ Automation Test Scripts and managed testing activities using Selenium for Web Applications and Desktop apps with Chromium-based renderings thereby reducing 50% of the regression testing effort. (3 Member Team)
- Developed and maintained 200+ Automation Test Scripts for Mobile apps using Appium with Perfecto cloud and reduced 30% of the testing effort with 30% of test coverage. (3 Member Team)
- Worked on developing a High-level custom common framework that could be used for any web application developed based on predefined standards on Angular components. As a by-product, Project team was able to deliver In Sprint automation.

CORE SKILLS

Functional & Exploratory Testing, Dynamics 365 CRM Functional Consultant

Insurance, Banking, Dynamics 365 CRM, ECM, CCM

Java with Selenium Web Driver

TestNG , Spec-Run , Junit

Postman, Rest API, SOAP, Swagger

Appium (los and Andriod), Perfecto

Easy Repro Framework , Inbuilt Codeless Tools

BDD, Cucumber, Spec flow, Hybrid Framework

Gradle , Maven , Ant

DQL, SQL

SVN , Git , Azure Repo , Azure Pipelines , YAML , Jenkins

Azure TestPlan

Non Functional (Dynatrace & Nexthink)

Agile , Scrum , Kanban.

SUPPORTIVE SKILLS

Test Manager | Test Designing, Planning, Executing and Reporting | People Management | Digital Experience

CRM (Salesforce, Microsoft Dynamics 365), Wealth Management & Digital Banking

Guidewire Policy Center, ECM (OpenText Documentum, D2, xCP, Kofax, OpenText xPression)

Documentum Core Development | Backend Development | Understanding of Web Architecture |

IBM MQ | Autosys | Sumo Logic | Custom Centralized Reporting for UI And API | Unified Custom UI Framework

ITIL | ServiceNow | Production Releases & Change Management |

WORK EXPERIENCE

Associate Cognizant

09/2018 - 03/2020

Chennai

Roles & Achievements

- Estimating, prioritizing, planning, and coordinating testing activities.
- Involved in the design and implementation of Selenium Web driver scripts, Executing test scripts and reviewing results, reporting and documenting technical issues.
- Automated backend Documentum Systems for creating folder structures and bulk import of documents into the server-side by developing custom utilities.
- Worked on testing the PDF renditions and XML Feeds.
- Achieved 100% automation on Monitoring Client Apps, Content Servers, DA jobs, Application Servers health, and Core SOAP API Services and reduced 1 FTE as Cost saving.
- Achieved automation in maintaining the data quality of different environments (Dev, QA, UAT).

Program AnalystCognizant

09/2015 - 09/2018

Chennai

Roles & Achievements

- Responsible for gathering user requirements, updating User Requirement documentation, and gaining deeper knowledge of Enterprise level architecture handling 1 million transactions per week.
- Gained deeper exposure to ITIL, SDLC, and STLC processes and domain exposure to Policy Lifecycle, Claims process, and Reinsurance backgrounds.
- Got Exposure to ECM tech stacks (OpenText Documentum, OpenText Xpression), Guidewire Policy Center and a lot of open source solutions.
- Handled Application maintenance on delivering enhancement on SOAP services built upon Spring Framework, DFC API Predominantly, and XML operations with XSLT.

EDUCATION

Graduation : BE (Electrical and Electronics)Velammal College of Engineering and Technology

07/2011 - 04/2015

Madurai, TamilNadu

LEARNING MAPS

Non Functional Test Automation (Jmeter) QAOps in Digital
Transformation

Playwright with JS/TS

ACHIEVEMENTS

Contextual Masters™ Award

TCS Internal Award for fostering growth of their clients via contextual skills

Best Automation Team Award

Capgemini Internal Award for the Best team within Business Unit

Associate of Quarter

Cognizant Internal award for Adopting Digital Transformation

CERTIFICATIONS

Dynamics 365 Fundamentals CRM (MB 910)

Fundamentals of Dynamics 365 CRM From Microsoft

Azure Fundamentals (AZ 900)

Fundamentals of Cloud Services From Microsoft

Agile Software Development

University of Minnesota

ISTQB Foundational

International Software Testing Qualifications Board

LANGUAGES

English

Full Professional Proficiency

Tamil

Full Professional Proficiency

Hindi

Limited Working Proficiency

INTERESTS

Volunteering

Motorcycling, Teaching